Tyler Young

Technical Writer

Website: tyler-young.com Email: tyler@tyler-young.com Phone: (360) 601-4398

Technical Writer with 9 years of experience in crafting user-friendly technical instructions for all skill levels. My goal is to use my documentation writing expertise, technical knowledge, and customer support experience as part of a growing team focused on customer success.

Experience

Senior Product Documentation Specialist

May 2022 - March 2023

Nucleus Security

- Responsible for all customer-facing documentation, including instructions for integrating with dozens of third-party services.
- Maintained and improved the documentation website itself, built using Document360, including implementing custom JavaScript to add additional features.
- Worked closely with product, marketing, and sales to support the definition and release of multiple features
- Implemented a plan to bring all documentation up to WCAG2AA accessibility standards.

Technical Writer

October 2020 – April 2022

Fastly

- Responsible for all customer-facing documentation related to security products, including web application and API protection, bot protection, edge-based WAF, and other cloud security features.
- Maintained and improved multiple documentation websites built with Hugo and Jekyll on AWS and GCS, adhering to WCAG2AA accessibility standards.
- Created training curriculum and instructed new team members in the use and troubleshooting of company security products.

Support Engineer

February 2018 – October 2020

Signal Sciences (acquired by Fastly)

- Sole technical writer, created and maintained all customer-facing documentation.
 - Managed and defined technical support for enterprise and SMB customers.
 - Maintained documentation website built with Hugo on AWS, including deploying structural improvements.
 - Created training curriculum and instructed new team members in the use and troubleshooting of products.
 - Owned company status page and was responsible for managing incidents and public messaging.

Education

Bachelor of Arts, Psychology

June 2013

Willamette University

Achievements

Published research paper

August 2013

Dixon, K., Young, T. & Miller, J. (2013, August). The Influence of Selective Attention during Memory Retrieval on Subsequent Memory Performance in Young and Older Adults. Poster session presented at the 35th Annual Conference of the Cognitive Science Society. Berlin, Germany.

Eagle Scout May 2008

Skills

Technical writing, documentation management, information security, SaaS, JIRA, Git, Markdown, HTML, CSS, WCAG, Google Analytics, Hugo, Jekyll, AWS, GCS, Linux, web hosting, DNS, C#, Python, JavaScript, Go, SQL